VOA Special English Technology Report.
Smartphones, tablet computers, and e-readers have become a part of everyday life for many
people.
They have also led to an explosion in the number of mobile applications.
There is an app for just about anything you can think of, and more and more apps
are being created every day.
Robert Denazi is a Hollywood movie producer.
He is perhaps best well known as the executive producer of Flightplan, the 2005 movie starring
actress Jodi Foster.
His most recent claim to fame is as co-developer of a new app called VoiceCal.
It is a mobile calendar app that uses voice recognition software.
Users are able to enter appointments into their iPhone calendar without having to type
in the information.
He said although he has a mobile phone, he had to stop what he was doing to put things
in his calendar.
In his words, it got to the point where I just wasn't using the calendar on my iPhone
and neither was anybody else that I knew.
Robert Denazi decided there had to be a better way.
So he teamed up with a friend who is a developer.
The two used voice recognition software from a company called Nuance to build VoiceCal.
He says when you use VoiceCal, you can say any event you want to put into your calendar
and it will appear there.
If you have two or more events to add to the calendar, you separate them by using
the word also.
Mr. Denazi says all of this can be done hands-free.
In settings, you can make it fully automatic, so I don't have to touch anything.
He says Robert Denazi says there is a great need for an app like VoiceCal among busy
businessmen like himself.
He hopes the app will be successful over the long term.
He says in the movie business, you can do all the advertising in the world and that can get
you a great opening weekend, but if the movie is not good, it will die off.
So really what supports a film just like what supports an app is word of mouth.
Matt Kozlov is the head of a startup technology company called Moonshark in Los Angeles, California.
The company makes game apps for mobile devices.
It's an exploding marketplace right now, he says.
There are hundreds of millions of devices out there right now that we can reach.
Jennifer Lopez is helping Moonshark with a finger break dancing game called Dance Pad.
The company is also working with film director John Woo on an action game expected to be
released at the end of this year.
For VOA Special English, I'm Alex Villareal.